Jonathon Rigert

Web Developer, Architect, Director

jonrigert.com

(630) 439-4995
jonrigert@gmail.com
Michigan, 48154
in LinkedIn

Skills

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- CSS / SASS
- React
- NextJS
- React Native / React Native Web
- Redux / Redux Saga
- git
- Tailwind
- Styled Components / CSS-in-JS
- SQL and noSQL Databases
- RESTful APIs
- NodeJS
- Firebase
- Unit Testing (Jest, React Testing Library)
- Agile Development
- Integration with CMS Platforms
- Web Accessibility
- TurboRepo / Monorepo development
- CI/CD Pipelines and Actions

Introduction

A web developer, architect and leader with a diverse range of skills and interests. Offers over a decade of experience in building detailed web applications, committed to code quality, scalability, and best practices. Brings strong leadership qualities and a passion for mentorship, excels in highly collaborative environments.

Experience

Bounteous, Inc.

July 2015 - Present

Director, Web Application Development

- Serves as the primary point of oversight and escalation for numerous projects
- Leads initiatives to establish practice-wide coding standards and best practices
- Aids in diagnosing and resolving complex issues
- · Helped establish and facilitate a React Apprenticeship program, acting as leader and mentor
- · Assists in the pitching, estimating, and technical planning of both potential and ongoing projects
- Founded and directs the Bounteous Web Development Craft, a collaborative initiative dedicated to knowledge exchange, establishing best practices, and building a supportive community
- Contributes to the planning, architecture, and development of numerous projects from inception to completion
- Leads multiple teams of developers, responsible for the technical success of various projects
- Collaborates with a diverse array of clients to plan and execute projects, recognized as a trusted partner
- Works with a multitude of technologies, with a strong focus on React
- Spearheads the development and architecture of several internal projects

Previous Positions:

Associate Principal Front-End Architect (July 2021 - November 2021) Lead Front-End Developer (August 2020 - July 2021) Senior Front-End Application Developer (July 2015 - August 2020)

UnitedHealth Group / Optum

April 2014 - July 2015

Senior Web Developer

- Developed a large-scale digital health application in AngularJS, providing services to healthcare consumers and providers
- Senior member of the Core/Foundational team that constructed the application framework utilized by various development teams
- Part of most feature planning, architectural design and development
- Integral to the development of the "Toolkit", a JavaScript/AngularJS library that allows sharing of critical components across multiple web applications
- Member of the support team that troubleshoots environmental issues and supports major releases of the application
- Contributed to the development of an internal web application designed to streamline weekly status reporting for developers

Command Transportation

October 2012 - March 2014

Software Developer

- Member of the team responsible for developing an internal software system utilized by the sales and dispatch team, which tracks and aligns customer loads with carrier trucks
- Implemented new features and maintained existing platforms in WPF, C# and VB.NET
- Primarily responsible for most user interface development, collaborating closely with the design team to bring their concepts to life
- Part of the support team that handles and fixes bugs reported by users
- Dedicated time to engage with users directly, observing their interactions with the software to gather valuable feedback and insights.

Jonathon Rigert

Web Developer, Architect, Director

jonrigert.com

(630) 439-4995
jonrigert@gmail.com
Michigan, 48154
in LinkedIn

Applied Systems, Inc.

March 2010 - September 2012

Software Developer

i

i

- Tasked with maintaining and updating insurance agency automation software applications in VB6 and VB.NET
- Developed new features for existing applications, updated existing functionalities, remediated defects, and rebuilt out-of-date assemblies and applications using more modern technologies
- Responsible for multiple conversions from 16-bit C++ to VB.NET to ensure compatibility with 64-bit operating systems and modern computer standards

Education

DeVry University - Addison, IL

2005 - 2009

Bachelor of Science, Game and Simulation Programming